Privacy Policy
==============

We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting your personal data. This privacy policy describes how we look after any personal data we process when you visit our website or use our products or services, and tells you about your privacy rights and how the law protects you.

Important information and who we are
------------------------------------

### Data Controller

Bloop AI Limited is the data controller and responsible for your personal data (collectively referred to as "Bloop", "we", "us" or "our" in this privacy policy). If you have any questions about this privacy policy, including any requests to exercise your legal rights, please contact us using the details set out below.

### Contact details

If you have any questions about this privacy policy or our privacy practices, please contact us in the following ways:

* Full name of legal entity: Bloop AI Limited
* Email address: contact@bloop.ai
* Postal address: Bloop AI Limited, First and Second Floor, 30 St John's Ln, London, EC1M 4NB, UK

You have the right to make a complaint at any time to the Information Commissioner's Office (ICO), the UK regulator for data protection issues (www.ico.org.uk). We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach the ICO so please contact us in the first instance.

### Changes to the privacy policy and your duty to inform us of changes

We keep our privacy policy under regular review and may update it from time to time.

It is important that the personal data we hold about you is accurate and current. Please keep us informed if your personal data changes during your relationship with us.

### Third-party links

This website may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. When you leave our website, we encourage you to read the privacy policy of every website you visit.

The data we collect about you
-----------------------------

Personal data, or personal information, means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. It does not include data where the identity has been removed (anonymous data).

We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you which we have grouped together as follows:

* Identity and Contact Data includes name, email address and telephone numbers.
    
* Technical Data includes internet protocol (IP) address, your login data, browser type and version, and other technology on the devices you use to access this website.
    
* Usage Data includes information about how you use our website, products and services.
    
* Marketing and Communications Data includes your preferences in receiving marketing from us and your communication preferences.

We may also collect, use and share Aggregated Data such as statistical or demographic data for any purpose. Aggregated Data could be derived from your personal data but is not considered personal data in law as this data will not directly or indirectly reveal your identity. For example, we may aggregate your Usage Data to calculate the percentage of users accessing a specific website feature. However, if we combine or connect Aggregated Data with your personal data so that it can directly or indirectly identify you, we treat the combined data as personal data which will be used in accordance with this privacy policy.

We do not collect any Special Categories of Personal Dataabout you (this includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health, and genetic and biometric data). Nor do we collect any information about criminal convictions and offences.

### If you fail to provide personal data

Where we need to collect personal data by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you, and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into with you (for example, to provide you with goods or services). In this case, we may have to cancel a product or service you have with us but we will notify you if this is the case at the time.

How is your personal data collected?
------------------------------------

We use different methods to collect data from and about you including through:

* Direct interactions. You may give us your Identity and Contact Data by filling in forms or by corresponding with us by post, phone, email or otherwise. This includes personal data you provide when you:
    
* subscribe to our service or publications;
    
* request marketing to be sent to you; or
    
* give us feedback or contact us.
    
* Automated technologies or interactions. As you interact with our website, we will automatically collect Technical Data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns. We collect this personal data by using cookies and other similar technologies. Please see our cookie policy for further details.

How we use your personal data
-----------------------------

We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:

* Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you.
    
* Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests.
    
* Where we need to comply with a legal obligation.

Generally, we do not rely on consent as a legal basis for processing your personal data, although when required by law we will get your consent before sending direct marketing communications to you via email or text message. You have the right to withdraw consent to marketing at any time by contacting us.

### Marketing

We will send you marketing when we have your permission to do so, or where we have another legal basis to do so.

### Change of purpose

We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If you wish to get an explanation as to how the processing for the new purpose is compatible with the original purpose, please contact us.

If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain the legal basis which allows us to do so.

Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.

Disclosures of your personal data
---------------------------------

We may share your personal data with the parties set out below.

* Service providers, such as Google, that we use to operate or manage or business, and who may be based outside of the UK.
    
* Third parties to whom we may choose to sell, transfer or merge parts of our business or our assets.

We require all third parties to whom we disclose date to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposes and only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.

International transfers
-----------------------

Many of our service providers are based outside the UK so their processing of your personal data will involve a transfer of data outside the UK.

Whenever we transfer your personal data out of the UK, we ensure a similar degree of protection is afforded to it by ensuring appropriate safeguards are implemented.

Data security
-------------

We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.

We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.

Data retention
--------------

### How long will you use my personal data for?

We will only retain your personal data for as long as reasonably necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, regulatory, tax, accounting or reporting requirements. We may retain your personal data for a longer period in the event of a complaint or if we reasonably believe there is a prospect of litigation in respect to our relationship with you.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal, regulatory, tax, accounting or other requirements.

Your legal rights
-----------------

Under certain circumstances, you have rights under data protection laws in relation to your personal data, including the right to request access to, correct of, or erasure of your personal data. Please contact us if you would like to exercise any of those rights.

_Updated 12th December 2022_

Product

Company

Socials
